Guide to the Edward Glass papers, 1940-1999.
Glass, Edward papers, 1940-1999.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edward Glass papers, 1940-1999.
22-1-3343
Edward H. (Edward Hadley) Glass, 1917-
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, lecture notes, subject files, biographical material, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, reports, lecture notes, subject files, biographical material, and photographs, relating to Glass' career in the Dept. of Entomology and the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station at Cornell University, his work in the Phillipines, and with the firm Rhodia.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Entomology at the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station in Geneva (1948-1982) and head of the department from 1969-1982.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, reports, lecture notes, subject files, biographical material, and photographs, relating to Glass' career in the Dept. of Entomology and the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station at Cornell University, his work in the Phillipines, and with the firm Rhodia.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Glass, Edward H. (Edward Hadley), 1917-; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of Entomology.; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.; Rhodia (firm)
Subjects:
Entomology--Study and teaching.
Places:
Phillipines.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Background, Personal Information
  - 1999 File (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Department of Entomology (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Documentation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Entomology 160, 161 (class) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Eudora, E-Mail, etc. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Geneva concerts, work notes, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Master's Thesis, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Malathion" Series (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Publications and CV (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gould Colman Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - University of Massachusetts, Correspondence and Information (Box 1, Folder 13)
- General Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1982-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14-27)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
- University of the Philippines Materials
  - Philippines, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - University of the Philippines, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Philippines, Magazine Notes (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - University of the Philippines, List of the pests of crops (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Philippines Project (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - University of the Philippines, Notes, letters, etc, Final Report. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reports on Insect Control Studies, Philippines, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Philippine Notes, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Rhodia, Inc.
  - Rhodia Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Rhodia Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Rhodia Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rhodia Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Rhodia Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rhodia Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Rhodia Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Rhodia-Southeast Asia --Final Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1958-Apr. 1959 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1959-Apr. 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1960-Apr. 1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1961-Apr. 1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1962-Apr. 1963 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1963-Apr. 1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1964-Apr. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1965-Apr. 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, May 1966, June 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Rhodia (Rhone-Poulenc) Reports, Feb. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Rhodia I (1-12), May 1954-Apr. 1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Rhodia II (1-6), May 1955-Apr. 1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Rhodia III (1-12), May 1956-Apr. 1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Rhodia IV (1-12), May 1957-Apr. 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Materials
  - Africa-Photos, Maps, Postcards, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ARI International Conference, McLean, VA, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Articles for Earthcare Network and the Sierra Club International (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - CGIAR Annual Report (Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - China Workshops, Apr. 6-8, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chinese IPM Group Visit, Oct. 14, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - CICP IMPnet (Consortium for International Crop Protection) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - CICP Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Conservationist" Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Conference on Resistance Management, Oct. 25-26, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - CSREES Review, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Department Review, Entomology, Mar. 25-28, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Ecology of Pest Management Course, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - ESA (Entomological Society of America), Houston meeting, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - ESA, Houston Meeting-Presidential Address, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Ford Foundation, Ecology of Pest Management, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Keith Johnson (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Lab Rearing (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Lecture Notes on IPC for Research Management Trainees, Aug. 22, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Life History of OFM (Oriental Fruit Moth) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Machinery Information, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Talks, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - National IMP Information and Meeting, Nov. 8 and 9, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Notes on Remarks Made at Party for Roelof, RE; Wolf Award, Jan., 17, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Seminar on Evolution of Entomology at Geneva, June 24, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Speeches on Europe (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Station Club Dinner, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Steering Committee Nominations, Managing Pesticide Resistance (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Staff Photographs (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Steve Maquire File and Information (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - M. E. H. File, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Thurston-Field Trips (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Trip Report-Senegal and Nigeria, Pest Management Materials, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - "Value of Insecticidal Treatment Against Moths of the Red-banded Leaf Roller Control" (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - West Coast, Sept. 9-25, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - World Bank Contract, Correspondence, Reports and Papers, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - World Bank Seminar-Notes, Apr. 6, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "Joke File" (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Agricultural Experiment Station History Materials-Geneva, NY
  - Station History Correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - History Interviews (NYSAES), 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - History NYSAES, Minutes of Planning Meetings, May 21, 1991, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous, Station History Book (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Station History-Quik Mail, Mar. 29-May 26, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 50)